{"name": "D03 2020-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to the expression below? \u22127(5a \u2212 b) + 3(\u22128b + a) ", "choices": {"A": "\u221238a \u2212 31b ", "B": "\u221234a \u2212 25b ", "C": "\u221234a \u2212 17b", "D": "\u221232a \u2212 25b", "E": "\u221232a \u2212 17b"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. For Bill\u2019s birthday party, his parents will pay $35 for the cake plus $15 per person for catering expenses. They will spend at most a total of $300 for his party. The greatest integer in the solution set of one of the following inequalities gives the maximum number of people,  p, who can attend the party. Which one? ", "choices": {"A": "p + 50 \u2265 300", "B": "p(15p + 35) \u2265 300", "C": "(35 + 15)p \u2264 300", "D": "15p \u2264 300", "E": "15p + 35 \u2264 300"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3.  The number 312.8 is 34% of x. What is the value of x rounded to the nearest whole number?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "11", "C": "106", "D": "920", "E": "10,635"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. For  shown below, point S is on RT, the length of RS is 8 cm, and the length of ST is 18 cm. What is the distance, in centimeters, between T and the midpoint of RS ?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "17", "C": "18", "D": "22", "E": "26"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. A certain committee is composed of 9 juniors and 11 seniors. Two different members of the committee will be randomly selected for 2 different leadership roles. Given that the 1st member who will be selected is a senior, what is the probability that the 2nd member who will be selected is a junior?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. What is the least common multiple of 60, 70, and 90 ?", "choices": {"A": "60", "B": "220", "C": "630", "D": "1,260", "E": "378,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. The Newton High School girls\u2019 softball team currently has a record of 8 wins, 5 losses, and 0 ties. What is the least number of its remaining 10 games the team must win to finish the season winning more than 50% of all the team\u2019s games?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "5", "D": "6", "E": "7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. For what value of  x is 2(x \u2212 12) + x = 24 true?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "4", "C": "12", "D": "16", "E": "24"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. The principal of Lowe High School (LHS) authorized a study to estimate the percent of the LHS student population that will attend a 4-year college after graduation. LHS students in honors courses were asked about their postgraduation plans, and their responses were recorded. Students in other courses were NOT included in the study. Which of the following phrases best describes the principal\u2019s study?", "choices": {"A": "Randomized census", "B": "Randomized experiment", "C": "Nonrandomized experiment", "D": "Randomized sample survey", "E": "Nonrandomized sample survey"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10.  Triangles \u25b3ABC and \u25b3A'B'C' are graphed in the standard(x, y) coordinate plane below.Triangle \u25b3A'B'C' is the image of \u25b3ABC under one of the following transformations. Which one ?", "choices": {"A": "90\u00b0 clockwise rotation about the origin", "B": "90\u00b0 counterclockwise rotation about the origin", "C": "Horizontal translation", "D": "Reflection across the x-axis", "E": "Reflection across the y-axis"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Banu will build a fence around a rectangular 30-foot-by-25-foot play area. Given that fencing costs $4.05 per foot, how much will the fencing cost for Banu to completely surround the play area?", "choices": {"A": "$445.50", "B": "$344.25", "C": "$324.00", "D": "$268.00", "E": "$222.75"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. The diagonal of a rectangular flat television screen is 26.0 inches. The width of the screen is 22.7 inches, and the height of the screen is 10.0 inches less than the width of the screen. Which of the following is closest to the area, in square inches, of the television screen?", "choices": {"A": "144", "B": "165", "C": "288", "D": "330", "E": "590"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. For all a\u22600,   is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. An ellipse with a major axis of length 6 inches and a minor axis of length 4 inches is inscribed in a rectangle, as shown below. The region inside the rectangle but outside the ellipse is shaded. What is the area, in square inches, of the shaded region?(Note: The area,  A, of any ellipse can be found by the formula  A =  \u03c0ab where  a is  the length of the major axis and  b is  the length of the minor axis.)", "choices": {"A": "24 - 24\u03c0", "B": "24 - 12\u03c0", "C": "24 - 6\u03c0", "D": "6\u03c0", "E": "24 + 6\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Given , what is the value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. What is the largest possible product for 2 even integer whose sum is 18 ?", "choices": {"A": "11", "B": "19", "C": "77", "D": "80", "E": "81"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Juanita walked from her home to the bakery, first walking 0.3 miles due east and then 0.4 miles due north. What is the straight-line distance, in miles, from the bakery to Juanita\u2019s home?", "choices": {"A": "0.1", "B": "0.2", "C": "0.3", "D": "0.5", "E": "0.7"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18.  -  = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. The line with equation 2x + 5y = 9 is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. What is the slope of the line?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. Yolanda is calculating the weekly payroll for her small business. One employee earns $7.20 per hour and has worked 4 days this week:  hours the first day, 8 hours the second day,  hours the third day, and  hours the fourth day. Which of the following is the employee\u2019s pay for this week, before any deductions are made?", "choices": {"A": " $226.80", "B": " $225.00", "C": " $219.60", "D": " $131.40", "E": " $38.70"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What is the (x ,y ) solution, if one exists, to the system of equations y = 2x + 6 and 6x + 12 = 3y?", "choices": {"A": "(-3, 0)", "B": "(-2, 0)", "C": "(0, 4)", "D": "(0, 6)", "E": "There is no solution to this system."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. Sets  A, B, and  C are defined below.        A = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9}        B = {2, 4, 6, 8}        C = {4, 8}A number will be randomly selected from  A. What is the probability that the selected number will be an element of  C and an element of  B ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": "1"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Maranda is going to a leadership conference and was given the map below to guide her to the Conference Center. The map has no scale, but she knows that the distance between Exits 77 and 79 on Interstate 29 is 2 miles. On the map, this distance is  of an inch. She plans to exit Interstate 29 at Exit 77, travel on 41st Street to Cliff Avenue, and then proceed on Cliff Avenue to the Conference Center. The distance on the map from Exit 77 to the Conference Center over this route is  inches. What is this distance, in miles?", "choices": {"A": " 4", "B": " 5", "C": "9", "D": "12", "E": "18"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The histogram below shows the results of a survey of 100 people. Each person identified the number of hours per week that they watch TV. How many people surveyed watch TV at least 4 hours per week?", "choices": {"A": " 57", "B": " 38", "C": "28", "D": " 21", "E": "19"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Each side of a square is 4 cm long. One vertex of the square is at (6, 2) on a square coordinate grid marked in centimeter units. Which of the following points on the grid could be another vertex of the square?", "choices": {"A": " (10, 2)", "B": " ( 7, 3)", "C": "( 2, 5)", "D": "( 1, \u22125)", "E": "(\u22124, 2)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. An outlier is added to the data set below. Which of the following pairs of statistics has no change in value as a result of the addition of the outlier?  {60, 63, 66, 70, 72, 72, 73, 73, 73, 75}", "choices": {"A": " Mean and median", "B": " Mean and mode", "C": "Mean and range", "D": " Median and mode", "E": " Median and range"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Given that \u2220R is the included angle between the 2 congruent sides of the isosceles triangle \u25b3RST, and the measure of \u2220R is 50\u00b0, what is the measure of \u2220S ?", "choices": {"A": "  20\u00b0", "B": "  50\u00b0", "C": " 65\u00b0", "D": "  80\u00b0", "E": "  130\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the distance, in coordinate units, from  to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Hikers\u2019 World Foods sells raisin-nut mix in bulk to stores. The dollar amount per pound, P(x), for a store to purchase x pounds of raisin-nut mix from Hikers\u2019 World is given by the function below.                To the nearest $0.01, which of the following dollar values is equal to the total price for a store to purchase 100 pounds of raisin-nut mix in a single order from Hikers\u2019 World?", "choices": {"A": " $350.00", "B": " $359.00", "C": " $440.00", "D": " $616.00", "E": " $903.50"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. In right triangle \u25b3ABC show below, sin C =  and the length of AB and the length of AB is 14 inches, What is the length, in inches, of AC ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "10", "D": "19.6", "E": "24"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. The 1st term of a geometric sequence is 27, and the 4th term is 64. In terms of n, what is the nth term of the sequence?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. A series of transformations are applied to the graph in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. The graph below is reflected across the x-axis. The new graph is reflected across the y-axis. This new graph is rotated 90\u00b0 clockwiseabout the origin.                           ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. What is the least positive number that has a remainder of 3 when divided by 6 and a remainder of 6 when divided by 9 ?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "18", "C": "24", "D": "42", "E": "72"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. What rational number is exactly halfway between  and  on the real number line?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. On a certain day in Katie\u2019s yard, the average rate of change in temperature per hour between 1 p.m. and 11 p.m. was \u22122\u00b0F per hour. The temperature in Katie\u2019s yard at 11 p.m. that day was 42\u00b0F. Which of the following was the temperature in Katie\u2019s yard at 1 p.m. that day?", "choices": {"A": "14\u00b0F", "B": "22\u00b0F", "C": "62\u00b0F", "D": "64\u00b0F", "E": "84\u00b0F"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Given that i is the imaginary unit, which of the following complex numbers is equal to (7 + 6i )\u00b2 ?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "85", "C": "13 + 84i", "D": "14 + 12i", "E": "85 + 84i"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Two motorcycles, starting at the same point at the same time, travel away from each other at a 90\u00b0 angle. One travels at 40 miles per hour and the other at 60 miles per hour. If they continue traveling at these constant rates, after about how many hours will they be 200 miles apart?", "choices": {"A": "1.4", "B": "2.8", "C": "3.2", "D": "7.7", "E": "8.7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Use the following information to answer questions 38\u201340.A website about birds made the 4 claims below about American robins.\n1. The population of American robins in 2015 was 320 million.\n2. The wingspans of all American robins can be fit to a normal distribution model that has a mean of 36.00 cm and a standard deviation of 2.50 cm.\n3. The maximum reported flight speed for an American robin is 3,168 feet per minute.\n4. A certain conservation organization will only consider American robins threatened  if the total number of American robins declines by at least 30% over a 10-year period.38.  Suppose the population of American robins increased each year from 2005 to 2015. The conservation organization will consider American robins threatened provided that their population in 2025 is no greater than what number?", "choices": {"A": "  960,000", "B": " 9,600,000", "C": " 22,400,000", "D": " 96,000,000", "E": "  224,000,000"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Use the following information to answer questions 38\u201340.A website about birds made the 4 claims below about American robins.1. The population of American robins in 2015 was 320 million.2. The wingspans of all American robins can be fit to a normal distribution model that has a mean of 36.00 cm and a standard deviation of 2.50 cm.3. The maximum reported flight speed for an American robin is 3,168 feet per minute.4. A certain conservation organization will only consider American robins threatened  if the total number of American robins declines by at least 30% over a 10-year period.39.  The population of American robins in 2015 is equal to  for some integer  k, What is the value of  k?", "choices": {"A": "-8", "B": "-7", "C": "2", "D": "7", "E": "8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Use the following information to answer questions 38\u201340.A website about birds made the 4 claims below about American robins.1. The population of American robins in 2015 was 320 million.2. The wingspans of all American robins can be fit to a normal distribution model that has a mean of 36.00 cm and a standard deviation of 2.50 cm.3. The maximum reported flight speed for an American robin is 3,168 feet per minute.4. A certain conservation organization will only consider American robins threatened  if the total number of American robins declines by at least 30% over a 10-year period.40. A certain robin flew for 15 seconds at the maximum reported flight speed cited by the website. Which of the following values is closest to the number of meters the robin flew during that time?(Note: 1 meter \u2248 3.3 feet)", "choices": {"A": "64", "B": "240", "C": "697", "D": "792", "E": "960"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Let  x be a real number. Which of the following statements is true for all possible values of  x?", "choices": {"A": "A. \u2212x &lt; x", "B": "\u2212x &lt; \u23aax\u23aa", "C": " x = \u23aax\u23aa", "D": "\u23aax\u23aa = \u23aa\u2212x\u23aa", "E": " \u2212\u23aax\u23aa = \u23aa\u2212x\u23aa"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, the 3 distinct points A(3, 5), B(6, 8), and C are collinear, and B is equidistant from A and C. What are the coordinates of C ?", "choices": {"A": "(4, 7)", "B": "(9, 11)", "C": "(1.5, 1.5)", "D": "(4.5, 6.5)", "E": "(7.5, 10.5)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. If 90\u00b0 \uff1c\uff1c180\u00b0 and sin=, then cos", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. The mean of 10 numbers entered into a computer statistics program was 75.0. One number was incorrectly entered as 73 instead of 78. When the 73 is replaced by 78, by how much will the mean increase?", "choices": {"A": "0.1", "B": "0.5", "C": "1.5", "D": "3.0", "E": "5.0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. At Mort\u2019s Sporting Goods Store, the sale price of a pair of athletic shoes is 30% off the regular price of the shoes. The sale price of the shoes is $84.00. What is the regular price of the shoes?", "choices": {"A": "$54.00", "B": "$64.62", "C": "$109.20", "D": "$114.00", "E": "$120.00"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Use the following information to answer questions 46\u201348.Data from a random sample of 335 car owners in a certain city are listed below. The table indicates the number of owners in 3 age brackets (16\u221225, 26\u221245, 46\u221260) who own cars from 3 car companies (A, B, C) in this city. Each owner in the sample owns only 1 car.46. Two car owners from this sample will be chosen at random. Given that no owner is chosen twice, which of the following expressions gives the probability that both owners chosen will be from the same age bracket?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Use the following information to answer questions 46\u201348.Data from a random sample of 335 car owners in a certain city are listed below. The table indicates the number of owners in 3 age brackets (16\u221225, 26\u221245, 46\u221260) who own cars from 3 car companies (A, B, C) in this city. Each owner in the sample owns only 1 car.47. For those in the sample who are 26 to 45 years old, which of the following values is closest to the average number of car owners per company?", "choices": {"A": "37", "B": "45", "C": "52", "D": "112", "E": "155"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Use the following information to answer questions 46\u201348.Data from a random sample of 335 car owners in a certain city are listed below. The table indicates the number of owners in 3 age brackets (16\u221225, 26\u221245, 46\u221260) who own cars from 3 car companies (A, B, C) in this city. Each owner in the sample owns only 1 car.48. A circle graph will be drawn with 3 sectors each representing the proportion of owners from Company A, B, and C who are 16 to 25 years old. What is the measure of the central angle for the Company A sector of the graph?", "choices": {"A": "5\u00b0", "B": "17\u00b0", "C": "20\u00b0", "D": "43\u00b0", "E": "72\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The vertices of \u25b3PQR are given in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. What is the area, in square coordinate units, of \u0394PQR ?", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "25", "C": "30", "D": "48", "E": "50"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. The table below gives values of the functions f and g at different values of x. What is  ?", "choices": {"A": " -6", "B": " 1", "C": " 2", "D": " 3", "E": " 7"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Joe, Carmen, and Dave each receive an allowance. The ratio of Joe\u2019s allowance to Dave\u2019s allowance is 3:2, and the ratio of Dave\u2019s allowance to Carmen\u2019s allowance is 3:4. What is the ratio of Joe\u2019s allowance to Carmen\u2019s allowance?", "choices": {"A": " 1:2", "B": " 1:6", "C": " 2:5", "D": " 3:4", "E": " 9:8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. The figure below shows a flower bed consisting of 3 regions each bordered by garden edging. The edging forms 3 concentric circles with the distance between successive borders equal to the radius, r meters, of the smallest circle. The length of edging needed for the border of the smallest region is 10 meters. What is the total length, in meters, of edging needed for the borders of all 3 regions? ", "choices": {"A": " 30", "B": "60", "C": " 90", "D": "110", "E": "140"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. If ln x = 2, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": " ", "C": "2e", "D": "e", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. The first 4 elements of a pattern are shown below. Each element is composed of small squares that are 18 inches wide and 18 inches long. Each element is a square with both dimensions 18 inches less than the dimensions of the next element. What is the perimeter, in feet, of the 5th element?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "7.5", "C": "20", "D": "25", "E": "30"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. For all positive x, which of the following is equal to \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. In \u0394ABC shown below, the given side lengths are in meters. Which of the following expressions gives the area, in square meters, of \u0394ABC ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The simple interest for 1 year for an investment was $372. If the interest rate had been 1% higher for this investment, the simple interest for 1 year would have been $434. How much money was invested?", "choices": {"A": "$62", "B": "$520", "C": "$620", "D": "$5,200", "E": "$6,200"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. For what values of b does the equation x\u00b2 + bx + 1 = 0 have no real solutions?", "choices": {"A": "All b &lt; 0", "B": "All b &lt; 1", "C": "All b &lt; 2", "D": "0 &lt; b &lt; 4", "E": "\u22122 &lt; b &lt; 2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, the endpoints of the major and minor axes of the ellipse are labeled. Which of the following equations determines the ellipse?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. One root of the quadratic polynomial ax\u00b2 + 13x \u22126 is equal to \u22123. Which of the following binomials is a factor of ax\u00b2 + 13x \u22126 ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "x - 3", "D": "x - 5", "E": "x + 5"}, "correct": "A"}]}